PHYSICAL: WELCOME TO MONGOLIA
실물: 몽골에 오신 것을 환영합니다
It's your last arrow.
마지막 화살입니다.
Yeah, last arrow.
네, 마지막 화살입니다.
Don't pull back too hard.
너무 세게 뒤로 당기지 마세요.
Good aim.
좋은 목표입니다.
No!
안돼!
ORKHON: 0
오르혼: 0
Zero points.
0점.
Orkhonbayar is
오르콘바야르는
definitely a city boy.
확실히 도시 소년이군요.
It was my first time shooting a bow, so...
활을 쏘는 건 처음이라...
I think the three of us...
내 생각엔 우리 셋이...
Final match?
최종전?
AMOTTI VS. EDDIE VS. ORKHON
아모티 VS. 에디 대. 오르콘
- Amotti. - Pull back hard.
- 아모티. - 세게 뒤로 당기세요.
I won't pull back hard.
세게 물러서지는 않겠습니다.
I'm going with technique.
나는 기술로 갈거야.
Hey...
안녕...
INEFFECTIVE TECHNIQUE
비효과적인 기술
You really have to pull back hard.
정말 세게 뒤로 물러나야 합니다.
Amotti will end up cleaning.
아모티가 청소를 끝내겠습니다.
I can't do anything in this cold.
이 추운데 아무것도 할 수가 없어요.
I'm definitely an apartment boy.
나는 확실히 아파트 소년입니다.
Yeah.
응.
Show us what you got, Eddie.
당신이 무엇을 얻었는지 보여주세요, Eddie.
EDDIE DODGES POOP PENALTY
에디가 똥 페널티를 피하다
Orkhon!
오르콘!
Good aim.
좋은 목표입니다.
He's got this.
그는 이것을 가지고 있어요.
Where did it go?
어디로 갔나요?
AMOTTI: X, EDDIE: O, ORKHON: X
AMOTTI: X, EDDIE: O, ORKHON: X
(FOR REAL)
(진짜)
We have to make Orkhon clean.
오르콘을 깨끗하게 만들어야 합니다.
Please let me beat Orkhon.
오르콘을 이길 수 있게 해주세요.
I was laughing on the outside,
나는 겉으로는 웃고 있었지만
but inside I was serious.
그러나 속으로는 진지했습니다.
In order to beat Orkhon,
오르콘을 이기기 위해,
I'm going to give it my all
나는 내 모든 것을 바칠 거야
like it's Physical: Asia, Season 2.
Physical: Asia, 시즌 2와 같습니다.
This is our last chance.
이번이 마지막 기회입니다.
- What is it? - The ground!
- 그게 뭐죠? - 땅!
It touched the ground!
땅에 닿았어요!
This is the loser's match.
패자전입니다.
This and this? It's okay.
이것과 이것? 괜찮아요.
All of this is okay.
이 모든 것은 괜찮습니다.
I'LL SHOOT IN FRONT OF THE TARGET
내가 쏠게 표적 앞에서
THE ABSOLUTE FINAL ARROW
절대적인 최종 화살표
He looks good.
그 사람 좋아 보여요.
He has the best stance.
그는 최고의 스탠스를 가지고 있습니다.
- You look like a veteran. - He looks the coolest.
- 당신은 베테랑처럼 보입니다. - 그 사람이 제일 멋있어 보여요.
He really has the best stance.
그는 정말 최고의 스탠스를 갖고 있어요.
FAILED
실패함
ORKHON GETS TO CLEAN THE POOP
ORKHON이 똥을 청소하다
Despite how cold it was today,
오늘은 아무리 추웠어도
we had a fun time doing archery.
우리는 양궁을 하며 즐거운 시간을 보냈습니다.
Now, we're going to see my show.
이제 우리는 내 쇼를 보러 갈 거예요.
Wow!
와!
Oh, okay then.
아, 그럼요.
FINISHED CLEANING THE POOP
똥 청소를 마쳤습니다
Wow, that's so cool!
와, 정말 멋지네요!
That's amazing.
놀라워요.
PHYSICAL: WELCOME TO MONGOLIA
실물: 몽골에 오신 것을 환영합니다
OCHIR'S PERFORMANCE VENUE
OCHIR의 공연 장소
Ochir said he was going to perform with his family.
Ochir가 그랬다고 하더군요 가족과 함께 공연할 거예요.
I'm really looking forward to it.
정말 기대됩니다.
This looks like a ger.
이것은 거처럼 보입니다.
It's designed like a ger.
거처럼 디자인되었습니다.
Wow, this is amazing.
와, 정말 놀랍네요.
It's a real circus stage.
실제 서커스 무대예요.
Seriously.
정말로요.
Come on, Ochir.
자, 오키르.
Why am I nervous?
내가 왜 긴장하나요?
1ST PERFORMANCE: OCHIR'S SOLO
첫 번째 공연: OCHIR의 솔로
I'm breaking out in a sweat.
땀이 뻘뻘 납니다.
He's balancing the whole time.
그는 내내 균형을 잡고 있습니다.
This is amazing.
정말 놀랍습니다.
He's incredible.
그는 정말 대단해요.
Hey, there's more.
아, 더 있어요.
What is it?
뭔데요?
What's he doing?
그 사람 뭐 하는 거야?
He's incredible.
그는 정말 대단해요.
That was amazing.
놀라웠어요.
He's so cool.
그는 정말 멋지다.
OCHIR'S DAUGHTERS: BOROGCHINGOO, SORKHOGTANI, SOROGCHIN
OCHIR의 딸들: BOROGCHINGOO, 소록타니, 소록친
OCHIR'S YOUNGEST DAUGHTER: SETSENGOO
OCHIR의 막내딸: 세트센구
She's cute.
귀여워요.
- She is.
- 그래요.
2ND PERFORMANCE: OCHIR'S CHILDREN
두 번째 공연: 오키르의 아이들
She looks like a bird.
그녀는 새처럼 생겼어요.
They're so pretty.
너무 예뻐요.
- What's this? - Wow.
- 이게 뭐죠? - 우와.
They're incredible!
정말 대단해요!
How do they move like that?
어떻게 그렇게 움직일까요?
Holy cow.
거룩한 소.
She put her feet on top.
그녀는 발을 위에 올려 놓았습니다.
How are they so flexible?
어떻게 그렇게 유연합니까?
They're so amazing.
정말 대단해요.
That's insane.
미친 짓이군요.
How did he have four daughters?
그에게는 어떻게 딸이 넷이나 있었나요?
Imagine how happy he must be to go home after work.
그가 얼마나 행복할지 상상해 보세요 퇴근하고 집에 가려고.
What?
무엇?
Who's that?
저 사람은 누구죠?
- Really? - Yeah.
- 정말요? - 응.
OCHIR'S WIFE: ALTANCHIMEG
OCHIR의 아내: ALTANCHIMEG
3RD PERFORMANCE: HUSBAND & WIFE
3차 공연: 남편과 아내
I just got chills.
방금 소름이 돋았어.
Seriously, this is so incredible.
정말로 이건 정말 놀라운 일이에요.
What a beautiful family.
정말 아름다운 가족이네요.
How amazing.
정말 놀랍습니다.
Their strength is...
그들의 힘은...
Wow, this is seriously...
와, 이거 정말...
This is insane.
이건 미친 짓이야.
- How are they doing that? - Feet.
- 저 사람들은 어떻게 하는 거죠? - 피트.
She's hanging from his feet.
그녀는 그의 발에 매달려 있습니다.
I almost teared up because it was so amazing.
거의 눈물이 나올 뻔했어요 너무 놀라웠기 때문입니다.
OCHIR RETURNS AFTER PERFORMING
OCHIR가 공연을 마치고 돌아왔습니다.
What's this long thing?
이 긴 것은 무엇입니까?
LAST PERFORMANCE: OCHIR'S WIFE & HIS STUDENTS
마지막 공연: 오키르의 아내와 그의 학생들
I've never seen this before.
이건 본 적이 없어요.
Holy cow, that was amazing!
이런 소, 정말 대단했어요!
It was totally amazing.
정말 놀라웠어요.
Gosh, I'm hot.
맙소사, 나 더워.
I'm sweating.
땀이 나네요.
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
OCHIR GOES ON STAGE
OCHIR가 무대에 오른다
Let's see.
어디 보자.
You want me to come up?
내가 올라오길 원하시나요?
I'm not doing that.
저는 그런 일을 하지 않습니다.
I can't do this.
이건 할 수 없어요.
Hold on!
잠깐만요!
No, I can't do that. Absolutely not.
아니요, 저는 그렇게 할 수 없습니다. 절대 그렇지 않습니다.
Oh, come on!
오, 어서!
No messing around!
장난하지 마세요!
No messing around.
장난하지 마세요.
You have to stop up here.
여기서 멈춰야 해요.
I can't do stuff like this.
저는 이런 일을 할 수 없습니다.
I just can't.
난 할 수 없어.
Why is it so hard to climb this?
이것을 오르는 것이 왜 그렇게 어려운가요?
ENDS UP LYING DOWN
결국 눕게 됨
SMILING
웃으면서
LOSES IT
잃다
Hey!
안녕하세요!
Hey, little brother.
안녕하세요, 동생님.
He's adorable.
그는 사랑스럽다.
All right, everyone. Let's take a bow.
알겠습니다, 여러분. 인사를 하자.
For everyone here today,
오늘 여기 모인 모든 분들을 위해
we put together our special family circus performance.
우리는 함께 모였습니다 우리 가족의 특별한 서커스 공연.
This is my wife and my daughters.
이들은 내 아내와 딸들입니다.
We're a true circus family.
우리는 진정한 서커스 가족입니다.
Tomorrow, we'll invite all of you to our home.
내일은 초대하겠습니다 모두 우리 집으로 가세요.
We'll prepare some delicious meals for you.
준비하겠습니다 당신을 위한 맛있는 식사.
I hope you'll have a good time with my family tomorrow.
즐거운 시간 보내시기 바랍니다 내일 가족들과 함께.
Why is that so hard to climb?
왜 그렇게 오르기가 어려운가요?
Hold on. How do I get down?
잠깐만요. 어떻게 내려요?
How do I get down?
어떻게 내려오나요?
Wait a minute.
잠깐만요.
PHYSICAL: WELCOME TO MONGOLIA
실물: 몽골에 오신 것을 환영합니다
OCHIR'S HOME
오키르의 집
He has a really nice house.
그는 정말 좋은 집을 갖고 있어요.
IT'S STILL DARK IN THE MORNING
아침에는 아직 어둡습니다
Jeez, that's so cold.
맙소사, 너무 추워요.
OCHIR'S FAMILY GETS READY TO GREET GUESTS
OCHIR의 가족이 준비를 마쳤습니다. 손님을 맞이하기 위해
KNOCK KNOCK
KNOCK KNOCK
Come in.
들어오세요.
Hello. You're the kids we saw yesterday.
안녕하세요. 당신은 우리가 어제 본 아이들입니다.
Holy cow.
거룩한 소.
Your home is already giving off New Year vibes.
당신의 집은 이미 빛을 발하고 있습니다 새해 분위기.
I love how this house feels.
이 집의 느낌이 너무 좋아요.
WELCOME TO OCHIR'S HOME
OCHIR의 집에 오신 것을 환영합니다
Hey, look at that.
야, 저것 좀 봐.
That's an insane family photo.
정말 미친 가족사진이군요.
It's probably the only one in the world.
아마도 세계에서 유일한 것일 겁니다.
Hey, younger guy.
안녕하세요, 더 젊은 친구입니다.
Oh, that's right.
아, 그렇군요.
If the host sits there,
주인이 거기 앉으면
you have to sit here, Dong-hyun.
동현아 여기 앉아야 해.
- Why? - The older guy sits here.
- 왜요? - 나이든 사람이 여기 앉아 있어요.
- Right, the rules. - Like yesterday.
- 그렇죠, 규칙이요. - 어제처럼.
Got it.
알겠습니다.
You're the elder.
당신은 연장자입니다.
Right, I'm the elder.
그렇습니다. 제가 장로입니다.
We came very early in the morning,
우리는 아주 이른 아침에 왔어요.
so we feel bad for the trouble you went through
그래서 기분이 안 좋아 당신이 겪었던 문제 때문에
to get everything ready.
모든 것을 준비하세요.
There's no need to worry at all.
전혀 걱정할 필요가 없습니다.
It's Mongolian tradition to welcome guests
손님을 환영하는 것은 몽골의 전통입니다
who have come a long way, so please relax and enjoy yourselves.
먼 길을 온 사람들, 그러니 편안하게 즐기시기 바랍니다.
No worries at all.
전혀 걱정하지 마세요.
-Bayarlalaa. - Bayarlalaa.
-Bayarlalaa. - 바얄랄라.
We're very thankful.
정말 감사드립니다.
I hope we'll have the opportunity
우리에게 기회가 있기를 바라요
to return the hospitality.
환대에 보답하기 위해.
We prepared a traditional Mongolian meal especially for you.
몽골 전통음식을 준비했어요 특히 당신을 위해.
This is airag.
에이라그입니다.
Fermented horse milk?
발효된 말 우유?
- I've never seen this before. - It's like Korean makgeolli.
- 나는 이것을 전에 본 적이 없습니다. - 한국 막걸리 같아요.
Mongolians enjoy this drink,
몽골인들은 이 음료를 즐겨 마십니다.
and they serve it to special guests.
그리고 그들은 특별한 손님에게 그것을 제공합니다.
I see.
알겠습니다.
But if you drink that much,
하지만 그렇게 많이 마시면,
won't you get completely drunk?
완전히 취하지 않을래?
You can hold your liquor.
술은 담으시면 됩니다.
Hey, it's cold. It's not warm.
야, 추워. 따뜻하지 않아요.
Guests who come over
오시는 손님
have to sing a song to bring good luck to the home.
노래를 불러야 해 집에 행운을 가져다주기 위해.
Really?
정말요?
Yes, really.
네, 정말요.
What song do I sing?
나는 어떤 노래를 부를까?
There are lots of kids, so I'll sing a kids' song.
아이들이 많아요. 그래서 어린이 노래를 부를게요.
There are three bears in a house
집에 곰 세 마리가 있어요
Daddy bear, mommy bear
아빠 곰, 엄마 곰
Oh, she doesn't look happy.
아, 그 사람 표정이 안 좋아 보여요.
And baby bear
그리고 아기 곰
Daddy bear is fat
아빠 곰은 뚱뚱해요
- Mommy bear is slim
- 엄마 곰은 날씬해요
- Baby bear is really cute
- 아기곰은 정말 귀엽습니다
- Shrug, shrug! Good job!
- 으쓱, 어깨를 으쓱! 잘했어요! - 으쓱, 으쓱! 잘했어요!
BABY BEAR FEELS DAZED
아기 곰이 멍한 느낌을 받음
How do you say, "I'm sorry" in Mongolian?
몽골어로 "미안해요"는 어떻게 말하나요?
This smells strong, like makgeolli.
막걸리 냄새가 강해요.
I'm sipping it to make it last.
마시려고 한 모금 마시고 있어요.
Down it in three gulps.
세 번에 들이키세요.
Okay.
알겠습니다.
He takes tiny sips, but his reactions are huge.
그는 한 모금씩 마시고, 하지만 그의 반응은 엄청납니다.
AMOTTI DRINKS TOO
아모티도 마신다
AS WELL AS THE HOST
호스트뿐만 아니라
He looks a little out of it.
그는 조금 이상해 보입니다.
And he's more talkative.
그리고 그는 더 말이 많아요.
PHYSICAL: WELCOME TO MONGOLIA
실물: 몽골에 오신 것을 환영합니다
Here's the khorkhog Amotti ordered.
여기 Amotti가 주문한 khorkhog가 있습니다.
It's khorkhog!
코호그입니다!
There's also fried dumplings and buuz, so help yourselves.
튀긴 만두와 부즈도 있습니다. 그러니 스스로 도와주세요.
I hope you enjoy the food.
맛있게 드시기 바랍니다.
This is so good!
정말 좋아요!
- Wow. - It's delicious.
- 와. - 맛있어요.
This is amazing. It's the best.
정말 놀랍습니다. 최고입니다.
It's so good.
정말 좋아요.
And it's barely seasoned.
그리고 양념도 거의 안 됐어요.
I'm curious about something.
뭔가 궁금해요.
Do the kids train with you regularly,
아이들이 정기적으로 당신과 함께 훈련합니까?
or did they practice only for yesterday's show?
아니면 연습을 했나? 어제 쇼에만?
We train and practice together regularly,
우리는 정기적으로 함께 훈련하고 연습하며,
but we specifically prepared yesterday's performance for you.
하지만 우리는 특별히 준비했습니다 어제의 공연은 당신을 위한 것입니다.
Right now, I'm teaching my kids
지금은 아이들을 가르치고 있어요
to pass on my expertise and knowledge of traditional Mongolian acrobatics,
내 전문지식과 지식을 전수하기 위해 몽골 전통 곡예,
but when they grow up,
하지만 그들이 자라면
they'll decide for themselves and follow their own paths.
그들은 스스로 결정할 것입니다 그리고 각자의 길을 따른다.
The children must be very proud
아이들이 정말 자랑스러울 것 같아요
of their father.
그들의 아버지.
I think your youngest is close in age to my second child.
막내가 나이가 많은 것 같아요 내 둘째 아이에게.
Really?
정말요?
If we go to Korea, I think our kids will hit it off quickly.
한국에 가면 우리 아이들은 금방 성공할 것 같아요.
My kids can teach your kids acrobatics.
내 아이들이 여러분의 아이들에게 곡예를 가르칠 수 있습니다.
My kids are learning a bit of gymnastics.
우리 아이들은 약간의 체조를 배우고 있습니다.
When kids use the trampoline at a kids' café,
아이들이 트램폴린을 사용할 때 키즈카페에서,
they usually just jump and fall over.
그들은 보통 뛰어내리고 넘어집니다.
But Ochir's kids will flip in the air.
하지만 Ochir의 아이들은 공중에서 뒤집힐 것입니다.
It'll be really amazing to watch.
보면 정말 놀라울 거예요.
- Parenting for a day, done in a snap. - In a snap.
- 하루동안의 육아가 순식간에 끝납니다. - 순식간에.
What I found amazing yesterday
어제 내가 발견한 놀라운 점은
was the hanging performance.
행잉 퍼포먼스였습니다.
I was so moved by it.
정말 감동받았어요.
Your whole family is amazing.
가족 전체가 정말 대단해요.
My wife took up acrobatics later in life.
내 아내는 나중에 곡예를 시작했습니다.
It was after we got married when she was about 25.
우리가 결혼한 후였죠 그녀가 25세쯤 되었을 때.
That's when she decided to become an acrobat.
그때 그녀는 결심했어요 곡예사가 되기 위해.
Wow, that's amazing.
와, 정말 놀랍네요.
It's not easy once you're an adult.
어른이 되면 쉽지 않습니다.
What did you do before becoming an acrobat?
무엇을 했나요? 곡예사가 되기 전에?
I worked for Korea Visa Application Center for about two years.
저는 한국비자접수센터에서 근무했습니다. 약 2년 동안.
I also worked for Mongolian Airlines.
저는 몽골항공에서도 근무했습니다.
Those jobs had nothing to do with circus performing.
그 일은 아무 상관이 없었어요 서커스 공연과 함께.
I turned an office worker into a circus acrobat.
회사원이 됐어요 서커스 곡예사로.
How hard did she have to train to catch up?
그녀는 얼마나 열심히 훈련해야 했나요? 따라잡으려고?
She became this good
이렇게 착해졌어
because she trained harder than anything on Physical: Asia.
왜냐면 그녀는 더 열심히 훈련했으니까 Physical: Asia의 그 무엇보다도요.
That must've been so hard.
정말 힘들었겠군요.
Was your training difficult?
훈련이 힘들었나요?
Was he very hard on you?
그 사람이 당신을 너무 심하게 대했나요?
Of course.
물론이죠.
- Of course.
- 물론이지. - 물론.
I think Ochir would've scolded her a lot.
내 생각엔 오치르가 그녀를 많이 혼냈을 것 같아요.
If I'd tried to scold her, I'd have only gotten into trouble.
내가 그녀를 꾸짖으려고 했다면, 난 곤경에 처할 뻔했어요.
OCHIR CALLS SOMEONE OVER
OCHIR가 누군가에게 전화를 걸었습니다.
Come here.
이리로 오세요.
I'm Narantsetseg.
저는 Narantsetseg입니다.
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
- 안녕하세요. - 만나서 반가워요.
You're a handsome man.
당신은 잘생긴 남자예요.
And your mother is very beautiful.
그리고 당신의 어머니는 매우 아름답습니다.
So I think you're handsome because you take after her.
그래서 당신이 잘생긴 것 같아요 왜냐하면 당신이 그녀를 닮기 때문입니다.
Last month was a difficult time for our family
지난달은 어려운 시기였습니다 우리 가족을 위해
because my father passed away.
아버지가 돌아가셨거든요.
It's been exactly one month.
정확히 한 달이 지났습니다.
He passed away the day before Physical: Asia aired.
그는 세상을 떠났습니다 방영 하루 전.
So we were in the hospital when the first episode aired.
그래서 우리는 병원에 있었어요 첫회가 방영됐을 때.
It was a very difficult time.
매우 힘든 시간이었습니다.
I offer my deepest condolences on your father's passing.
심심한 애도를 표합니다 네 아버지의 죽음에.
But I'm sure your father is watching you from above,
하지만 네 아버지는 확실해 위에서 당신을 지켜보고 있습니다.
filled with pride and joy at the life you're living.
자부심과 기쁨으로 가득 차 당신이 살고 있는 삶에서.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
I was happy that Physical: Asia
Physical: Asia를 즐길 수 있어서 기뻤습니다.
reached so many people,
너무나 많은 사람들에게 다가갔고
and that people around the world cheered for Mongolia.
그리고 전 세계 사람들이 몽골을 응원합니다.
But even though I felt joy and happiness,
하지만 기쁨과 행복을 느꼈지만,
my heart ached even more, as if it were breaking.
더욱 마음이 아팠어요 마치 부서지는 것처럼.
Before my dad passed away,
아버지가 돌아가시기 전에,
I told him I participated in Physical: Asia,
내가 그에게 말했어요 Physical: Asia에 참가했는데,
and that his name and mine were becoming known worldwide.
그리고 그 사람 이름과 내 이름도 세계적으로 알려지게 되었습니다.
He cried when he heard that.
그는 그 말을 듣고 울었습니다.
Even more people in Mongolia now
이제 몽골에는 더 많은 사람들이 있습니다
see you as a hero and support you,
당신을 영웅으로 보고 응원합니다.
so if your father were still here, he'd be even more pleased.
그래서 네 아버지가 아직 여기 계시다면, 그는 더욱 기뻐할 것입니다.
I imagine that part hurts you the most.
그 부분이 가장 마음이 아프실 것 같아요.
But as Orkhon said earlier,
그러나 앞서 Orkhon이 말했듯이,
I think he's always by your side, watching over you
내 생각엔 그 사람이 항상 네 옆에 있는 것 같아. 당신을 지켜보고
and supporting you in that way.
그런 식으로 당신을 지지하고 있어요.
So I hope everything continues to go well for you,
그래서 나는 모든 것을 희망합니다 계속해서 잘 지내고 있어.
and I'll also always support you, right by your side.
그리고 나도 항상 당신을 지지할 거예요. 바로 당신 곁에요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
There are so many people in Korea
한국에는 사람이 너무 많아요
who love Ochir and Orkhon.
Ochir와 Orkhon을 사랑하는 사람.
So I'd like to invite both of you to Korea someday.
그래서 두 분 모두 초대하고 싶습니다 언젠가 한국으로.
Some Korean fans have told me
몇몇 한국 팬들이 나한테 말했어
that I look a lot like the actor Kim Ji-hun.
나랑 많이 닮았어 배우 김지훈.
If I go to Korea, will it be possible to meet him?
내가 한국에 가면, 그 사람을 만날 수 있을까?
I'll try my best to make that happen.
그렇게 되도록 최선을 다하겠습니다.
Because you resemble Kim Ji-hun,
김지훈이랑 닮았으니까
you're known as "Mongolian Kim Ji-hun."
당신은 '몽골인 김지훈'으로 알려져 있어요.
Your nickname is actually "Mong Ji-hun."
실제 별명은 '몽지훈'이에요.
Mong Ji-hun.
몽지훈.
You look the same.
당신도 똑같아 보여요.
Totally the same.
완전히 똑같습니다.
TRANSFORMS INTO MONG JI-HUN
몽지훈으로 변신
You really resemble him.
당신은 그 사람과 정말 닮았습니다.
- Seriously. - So handsome.
- 진심이에요. - 너무 잘생겼어요.
Don't I look like Ma Dong-seok?
마동석 같지 않나요?
MONG DONG-SEOK
몽동석
You're right.
당신 말이 맞아요.
You really look like him.
당신은 정말 그 사람과 닮았어요.
We prepared some gifts for you.
당신을 위해 몇 가지 선물을 준비했습니다.
Thank you!
감사합니다!
It's a puffer jacket.
푸퍼재킷이에요.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
We're so grateful you came all the way from Korea,
와주셔서 정말 감사드립니다 한국에서 쭉,
shared such warm and meaningful conversations,
너무나 따뜻하게 공유했어요 그리고 의미있는 대화,
and enjoyed the meal we prepared.
우리가 준비한 식사를 즐겼습니다.
It truly meant a lot to us.
그것은 우리에게 정말 큰 의미가 있었습니다.
I hope the next time we meet, we'll be just as healthy and happy.
다음에 만날 때는, 우리도 건강하고 행복할 거예요.
Let's raise our glasses.
잔을 높이자.
Cheers.
건배.
- Cheers.
- 건배.
- Thank you.
- 감사합니다.
You're the best dad.
당신은 최고의 아빠예요.
PHYSICAL: WELCOME TO MONGOLIA
실물: 몽골에 오신 것을 환영합니다
Subtitle translation by: Jenny Kim
자막번역: 김제니